# ASLAM MUHAMMAD USMAN

Contact: (852) 55449576 · usman22aslam@gmail.com

### **ABOUT ME**

Solution-driven Web Developer adept at contributing to highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions and determining client satisfaction. With experience of working as a web developer intern in two different companies. Looking forward to working as a web developer.

#### **EDUCATION**

2019 - 2021 • The University of Hong Kong

Bachelor of Science in Information Management

2017 - 2019 · CIE Baptist University of Hong Kong

Associate Degree in Mobile Information Technology (Graduated with First Class Honours)

### EXPERIENCE

## 2021 MerkleTree Foundation, Hong Kong (JUNE 2021 - PRESENT)

Web Developer

- Developed an educational website using Reactjs and Nodejs backend with React-Bootstrap and FontAwesome for interactive and user friendly interface.
- Enabled teamwork with Github SourceTree for code management and made use of advanced Reactjs concepts like contextAPI, Url Parameters, Restful API and Async for data transfer among different components.
- Used Postgres database with PgAdmin4 for data management and Insomnia to test Express Server API calls.
- AWS S3 service was used for resource management and as a solution for image storage to minimize the loading time of website.
- Used AWS Ec2 as a cloud server to host Postgres and React App, with Pm2 for process management and Nginx as load balancer.

#### 2021 Preface Coding, Hong Kong (FEBRUARY 2020 - PRESENT)

Coding Teacher

- · Customized block coding courses focusing on scratch, java, Html, CSS, and App Inventor.
- · Equiped kids with basic programming, sequential thinking, and problem-solving skills.
- · Provided them with basic projects to let them have solid hands-on experience.
- · Consultation with parents about student's performance, abilities, and future potential studies.

#### 2020 Fleet Management Limited, Hong Kong (JUNE 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2020)

Web Developer Intern

- Developed a Web-App for a shipping company using React.is, Nodejs, JSON, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 4.
- · Worked with senior developers to use AWS services like RDS and Lambda to host the website.
- · Used Postgres database for data management and Postman for API testing.
- · Participated in Scrum Planning and daily sprint meetings to work with the team.
- Used different React.js libraries like FormIk, React DatePicker to develop a user-friendly interface and used GitHub repositories to keep track of the progress.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### MerkleTree Innovation Educational Website

MerkleTree is an educational website that provide ethnic minorities in Hong Kong with free STEAM education and many other opportunities such as financial planning and learning Chinese through engaging games. The website can be visited on the following link https://www.merkletreeinnovation.org/

#### Cinema Ticket Booking System

A program which was created with the help of object-orientated programming using java for a cinema. Main purposes include booking a ticket, selecting seats, and the payment system. This program was able to keep track of sold tickets and staff members could update movie timings and add new movies.

## **SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: Java, Python, C#, C++, Reactjs,
- Nodejs, Bootstrap 4, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, PHP
- · Project Management with GitHub and Scrum Planning
- SQL and Database Management Information Retrieval
- · User Interface Design with Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator,

Video Editing with Final Cut Pro

## LANGUAGES

- Enalish (Fluent)
- Urdu (Native)
- · Hindi (Fluent)
- · Chinese (Beginner)